SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with over 10+ years of experience and a deep passion for programming.

I specialize in responsive web and application development for small to medium size businesses. Have been in web development and programming in general for many years during that time I've worked on many different: project, difficulties, flat forms and teams.

I love solving problems and tackling new issues, always striving to find the most efficient solutions. As a fullstack developer, I can work on projects from the front to end.

SKILLS

I am proficient and experienced with full stack web Development:

- 1. Web (frontend and backend)
 - a. JavaScript/TypeScript
 - b. React, Vue, Angular
 - c. Node, Express, Nest
 - d. PHP, Laravel, Symfony, CI, YII
 - e. Material Design, AnD, Bootstrap, Tailwind, HTML/CSS

 - f. Grpahal g. Java, Python
- 2. Database
 - a. MySQL, PostgreSQL
 - b. MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB
 - c. Redis, Google Cloud Storage
- 3. Devops and Others
 - a. AWS, Heroku, Firebase
 - b. Jenkins, CI/CD
 - c. Docker
 - d. Unit T<u>e</u>st

EDUCATION

University of Macedonia

Master's Degree Computer Science 2008 - 2013

CONTACT

A: Skopje, Skopski, North Macedonia L: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ robert-dod

E: robert.dodson.dr@gmail.com

ROBERT DODSON

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Engineer Self-employed June 2021 - Present

Senior Full-stack Developer **EVERDRIN**

February 2019 - June 2021

- Improved a Fin Tech platform in the frontend side and API implementation in Vue/Nuxt, Larvel.
- Added 30+ components to be used in global app by using styled-components.
- Redesigned global state management system with Redux thunk.
- Improve performance by optimizing codes with modern JS and API handling.
- Developed admin panel with React and Node

Full-stack Developer Endeva

April 2017 – Jan 2019

- Built a powerful SaaS using VuelS and Vuex, Vuetify framework.
- Developed headles CMS with React.js, Node.js and Strapi
- Developed chrome extension app for video conferencing by using WebRTC and Socket.IO
- Updated and added new RESTful APIs by using Apollo GraphQL + AWSlambda function
- Implemented portfolio service for SEO, RSS and JSON-LD for better user experience.
- Integrated payent gateway (stripe API) and localized by using i18n

Full-stack Developer Innovation Jan 2014 - Apr 2017

- Upgraded architecture of an enterprise clothing platform React, Node, MongoDB, Firebase (+7% improved in numbers of request per second)
- Developed headless CRM by using PHP and **JavaScript**
- Redesigned database MySQL to MongoDB
- Conducted end-user traning upon completion of testing and prior to delivery.
- Developed price analysis platform depend on Price API and Google Merchant api with React and Node
- Developed and improved performance of +10 animation effects with costum styling.
- Suggested and integrated real time communication mechanism with socket.io and WebSocket
- Performed troubleshooting procedures to fix bugs and other technical issues